Achref Kachti

Business Intelligence Engineer

Tunis, Tunisia +216 93948649 achref.kachti@esprit.tn LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Data-driven Business Intelligence professional with extensive experience in gathering, analyzing and interpreting complex data sets to drive business decisions. I'm a certified Microsoft Data Analyst with a strong background in requirement gathering, data modelling, data visualization, implementation, delivery and support services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Intelligence Developer - Consultant

March 2023 - Now

Metam

Creation and development of complete analytical solutions for Microsoft D365 ERP customers:

- Collaborate with stakeholders to gather and document business requirements.
- Utilize advanced SQL querying techniques to extract and transform data from diverse sources.
- Model and Implement ETL processes with Azure Synapse Analytics and Azure Data Factory.
- Design and Implement Azure Analysis Services tabular models.
- Identify and develop KPIs, ensuring alignment with strategic objectives.
- Create complex DAX expressions and Power guery transformations.
- Design and develop interactive reports and intuitive dashboards using Microsoft Power BI.
- Build CI/CD pipelines in Azure DevOps.
- Provide comprehensive documentation and training materials to facilitate user adoption.
- Ensure client follow-up by delivering completed work at each sprint.

Conducted an R&D project to identify and integrate open-source alternatives to Power BI and Azure Synapse:

- Designed and implemented ETL pipelines in Mage AI using Python and SQL.
- Developed Sales, Purchases and HR reports utilizing complex SQL queries within Metabase.
- Provided leadership to the team in adopting and utilizing both Metabase and Mage AI.

Business Intelligence Instructor - Part time

Nov 2023 - Now

GOMYCODE

Provide future professionals with crucial expertise in Business Intelligence, with a focus on Power BI:

- Conduct comprehensive introductory sessions on Business Intelligence.
- Facilitate and mentor students understanding of project development best practices.
- Conduct weekly meetings and follow-ups to monitor and enhance student progress.

Business Intelligence Developer

Jan 2022 - Feb 2023

Digital Identity

Development and Implementation of a robust retail decision-making solutions, resulting 20% increase in sales:

- Prepared the functional and business requirements for the development of data feed reports.
- Designed, modeled and implemented the data warehouse using SQL Server.
- Extracted data from multiple sources, Transformed and Loaded them with Talend.
- Implemented a multidimensional cube with SSAS and created complex MDX queries.
- Utilized Python's Data Mining algorithms to perform in-depth analysis of retail data.

- Developed visually compelling and interactive reports using Microsoft Power BI.
- Developed and implemented web intelligence reports using ASP.NET and Angular.

Data Analyst Intern

DSI ESPRIT

June 2021 - Aug 2021

Contributed to the optimization of candidate selection processes resulting in enhanced recruitment efficiency:

- Conducted extensive web scraping activities to gather resumes from various online platforms.
- Developed and implemented a Python script to extract relevant skills and attributes from resumes.
- Employed advanced data preprocessing techniques to standardize and encode the extracted information.
- Designed and created a dynamic report using Microsoft Power BI, providing recruiters with real-time insights into candidate skillsets, experience levels, and suitability for specific job roles.

Business Intelligence Developer Intern

Feb 21 - June 2021

General Insurance Committee

Development and Implementation of a decision-making solution for insurance companies:

- Modeled a robust and scalable data warehouse infrastructure using PostgreSQL.
- Orchestrated the ETL processes using Talend, facilitating seamless integration of disparate data sources.
- Leveraged the descriptive and predictive analytics capabilities of Python to conduct in-depth analysis of historical insurance data, employing data mining algorithms, achieving 80% prediction accuracy.
- Designed and developed dashboards to monitor and track key performance indicators using Power BI.

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineering Degree

ESPRIT - Private Higher School of Engineering and Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst PL-300	May 2024
---	----------

Microsoft

Microsoft Certified: Azure Enterprise Data Analyst Associate DP-500 May 2023

Microsoft

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals DP-900 Apr 2023

Microsoft

SKILLS

Data Visualization Power BI, SQL Server Reporting Services "SSRS", Metabase

Data Analysis SQL Server Analysis Services "SSAS", R, Python

Data Integration Talend, SQL Server Integration Services "SSIS", Azure Synapse Analytics, Mage AI

SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, phpMyAdmin

Programming language HTML, CSS, C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native French Fluent English Fluent Spanish Beginner